hey guys this looks like a fun one we're
given a rectangle and a semicircle and
this distance of six right here and it
wants to know what is the area of the
rectangle this is day 10 of our Advent
calendar for the month of December we're
going to do 31 Katrina a puzzles in 31
days if you want to try it on your own
pause it right now because I'm going to
solve it in three two one the puzzle
asking for the area of the rectangle so
let's write out that formula the area of
a rectangle is base time height so we
just got to figure out what is the base
and what is the height first let's find
the center of the semicircle and draw
this radius that's part of the base and
then we can draw this radius of the
semicircle that'll be the height of our
rectangle and to finish up the base of
our rectangle it's not quite a full
radius so let's just give it a variable
X so now we can express the area of the
rectangle the base is x + r and the
height is equal to R and then we can
distribute that x * R is XR and r * R is
R 2 so the area of our rectangle is XR +
r 2 this looks important let's put an
ellipse around it and I don't think we
need this stuff anymore and let's move
this down here next let's swing this
radius down here let's label this other
unknown distance as y this YX and R make
a nice looking right triangle let's do
Pythagorean theorem it'll be x^2 + y^2
is equal to R 2 and then I see another
right triangle let's get rid of of this
radius and focus on this right triangle
and we can do Pagan theorem again it'll
be the quantity x + r^ 2 + y^2 = 6^ 2
now let's play around with this a little
bit x + r 2 is the same thing as x + r *
x + r and after we multiply this out
we'll have x^2 + 2xr + r 2 these two
things are the same so let's get rid of
this I'm noticing up here we have an x^2
+ y^2 so let's bring this X2 over here
so now these look the same and let's
bring this stuff up here so we know that
x^2 + y^2 is equal to r^ 2 so in the
place of this x^2 + y^2 let's substitute
r^ 2 and then r^ 2 + r 2 is 2 R 2 let's
smush all of this stuff together and
they both have a two in there let's
factor out that two 2 * what gives us
2xr that's XR and 2 * what gives us 2 R
2 that'll be R 2 and if you didn't fully
follow that just imagine Distributing
this two to both of these it bring us
back up here so this is the same thing
as this let's get rid of this and move
this up here next on the right hand side
this 6 squar can be changed into 36 and
now both sides of our equation can be
divided by two on the left hand side
these twos will cancel each other out
and on the right hand side 36 / 2 is 18
so now we have XR plus r 2 is equal to
18 but that's the same thing as our area
XR + r 2 so the place of this XR + r^ 2
let's substitute in 18 let's give it a
label of unit squared and this is the
answer to our question the area of this
rectangle is 18 units squared how
exciting this was day 10 of our Advent
calendar and this will be day 11 it's
asking us what's this angle but it
doesn't really seem to provide very much
other information how exciting